# Paurush Tiwari

BIMTECH, Plot no. 5, Knowledge Park 2 GREATER NOIDA, Uttar Pradesh, 201306 +919958862099 tipaurush@gmail.com

# Summary

Self-motivated Web Developer with satisfactory level of experience working on multiple projects. Compassionate and motivated Social Worker, with comprehensive knowledge and experience with social justice and systems affecting marginalized communities. Knowledgeable about social science research areas and study procedures. Passionate about developing and facilitating programs to support communities in need. Experienced in setting up and carrying out data analysis. Diligent, industrious and efficient in handling minute details with methodical approaches to gain insights into this field. Interested in role with company promoting best practices and offering diverse customer projects.

### Education

**JSSATEN**, Noida, Uttar Pradesh B.Tech. in Computer Sscience

Graduating - May 2022

**St. Joseph's School**, Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh High School Diploma

Graduated - May 2018

# **Employment History**

#### **RSSWLD NGO**

Web developer: http://www.ranganathansociety.org/

June 2019 - Present

- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for its website.
- Created eye catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity.
- Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices.

### Kyrion Technologies Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, Delhi

Data scientist Intern

June 2019 - July 2019

- Designed an algorithm called Twitter analysis to analyse tweets of various celebrities.
- Used Jupyter Notebook, R Studio and tablue to enter data into project database and provided updates on 10 days basis.
- Created over 3 research summaries and presented them to supervisors to advocate further research.
- Gathered, arranged and corrected research data to create representative graphs and charts highlighting results for presentations.
- Collected and recorded data at various field sites for later assessment and data analysis.

#### AIC BIMTECH, NCR, Uttar Pradesh

Web Developer Intern

January 2019 - January 2019

- Under the leadership of the technical head of the organisation, I learnt the basics of web development and started working on Django and node.js framework.
- Learnt and applied basics of HTML and CSS.
- Designed a website using HTML, CSS and backend with node.js.

### Trainings

**Data Science** 

HPE (Online)

In this training I got to learn about the Big Data and Data Science from scratch to a pretty good level that i was able to achieve the HPE certificate with an aggregate of 8.9

# **Projects**

#### **RSSWLD NGO**

I have been an executive member of Ranganathan Society for Social Welfare and Library Development since 2018. Through this NGO, I have been able to reach out to poor children, rag pickers and many more socially backward people of our society. It has been my pleasure that I could contribute for the welfare of our country in one way. There's a long road ahead and I believe this contribution will last longer.

### **Professional Skills**

Object Oriented Programming (OOP) Advanced

Languages: Java, Python, C++,C, R Advanced Advanced

MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint,

Outlook)

Web Developer Advanced **Data Collection** Intermediate

Advanced Django

Data Analysis Intermediate

# Work Samples

1. <a href="http://www.ranganathansociety.org/">http://www.ranganathansociety.org/</a>

2. Github Profile: <a href="https://github.com/MAJOR-BEAST">https://github.com/MAJOR-BEAST</a>

3. Portfolio link: https://major-beast.github.io/My-website/